Mikaila K Ivery

Front-End Developer

Brooklyn, New York · iverymikaila@gmail.com · mikailaivery.com

Front-end developer with proven experience in helping companies create and maintain a better code base for reusability. Capable of bridging any knowledge gaps through continuous learning from senior developers while still coaching novice developers. Experience in facilitating projects from concept to launch. Passionate about learning and growth with a desire to apply skills on a larger development team.

Key Skills	HTML CSS JavaScript	Adobe Creative Suite	Asynchronous JavaScript
•	Responsive Design	RESTful APIs	Testing/Debugging
	React.js	SEO	GitHub

Experience

Freelance Web Developer, Fyve Senses

Oct 2023 - Present

- · Worked as part of a four-person team and communicated in a professional and collegial way.
- Developed and designed the company website using popular JavaScript frameworks React.js and Framer Motion to create a visually appealing and user-friendly interface.
- Implemented effective search engine optimization strategies, including the use of keywords, tags, and meta-descriptions, resulting in improved website visibility and ranking.
- Integrated RESTful API into the web application to enhance its functionality and provide seamless connectivity with external services.
- Ensured consistent website performance by regularly updating and troubleshooting issues, and maintaining high-quality standards.

Freelance Web Developer, Boy Blondey co

Feb 2022 - Present

- Developed user interfaces with custom HTML, CSS, and JavaScript in the company's Shopify theme template which improved user satisfaction.
- Improved site resulted in increased company profits by 25% for Q1 and Q2 of 2023.
- Created accessible, responsive, and functional code that allowed web visitors on any device to have the same user experience.
- Designed and coded custom HTML email templates that work with any email provider.
- Maintained quality website functionality through ongoing updates and troubleshooting.

Freelance Web Developer, Waist Away by Moojy

May 2023 - Jul 2023

- Developed and designed custom HTML, CSS, and Javascript for the brand's Shopify theme template.
- Maintained quality website functionality through ongoing updates and troubleshooting.
- Use keywords, tags, and meta-descriptions in order to optimize website for search engine and ranking.

Education

Bachelor of Science in Software Engineering, Western Governors University

Aug 2023 - Present

- Study of engineering principles to design, develop, test, and analyze computer software.
- Gaining industry certifications including AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner, CompTIA Project+, and ITIL® Foundation Certification.
- Learning technologies such as C#, Python, JavaScript, etc.
- Relevant Coursework: Data Structures and Algorithms, Scripting and Programming Foundations, Software Design and Quality Assurance, Version Control, Cloud Foundations, etc.

Associate of Applied Science in Advertising Marketing Communications, Aug 2019 - Dec 2021 Fashion Institute of Technology

- Study of advertising, public relations, broadcasting, journalism, digital media, management, and international organizations.
- · Nominated NSLS member by the school dean.
- · Overall GPA of 3.4

Certifications	Web Development Certificate	2021 - 2022

Issued by SheCodes Workshops

HTML Email Bootcamp 2022

Issued by Noble Desktop

Foundation of Leadership Certificate 2021

Issued by National Society of Leadership and Success (NSLS)

School Projects Weather App

Technologies: Open Weather Map API, React.js

Source Code: GitHub

Dictionary App

Technologies: Dictionary API, React.js

Source Code: GitHub